ILGWU. Research Department. United States NIRA hearing records, 5780/163
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Research Department. United States NIRA hearing records
1933-1937.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Research Dept.
5780/163
5 cubic feet
5 linear feet
Records
This collection contains reports and records of hearings held by the United States National Industrial Recovery Administration between 1933 and 1937. Topics of these hearings include Code of Fair Practices and Competition, Conference of Code Authorities and Trade Association Code Committee Employment, Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair Competition, as well as hearings on amendments, history and violations of code.
5511153
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
July 2011
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, July 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Biographical / Historical
The Research Department of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU) supported the administrative operations of the Union. The Research Department was organized to coordinate the ILGWU's investigative operations. It provided Union leaders with information on wages, working conditions, economic conditions, and other matters in the women's garment industry. The Department also collected and housed documents from Union administrative staff that were deemed substantive and of lasting value to the Union, whether produced internally or externally. The information gathered by the Department was of particular value during labor disputes and contract negotiations.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains reports and records of hearings held by the United States National Industrial Recovery Administration between 1933 and 1937. Topics of these hearings include Code of Fair Practices and Competition, Conference of Code Authorities and Trade Association Code Committee Employment, Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair Competition, as well as hearings on amendments, history and violations of code.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780/045. ILGWU. Research Department records
5780/056. ILGWU. Research Department collected documents
5780/078. ILGWU. Research Department reports
5780/105. ILGWU. Research Department records
5780/123. ILGWU. Research Department records
5780/148. ILGWU. Research Department wages and hours files
5780/168. ILGWU. Research Department records
5780/175. ILGWU. Termination Analysis log books
5780/209. ILGWU. Research Department records
General
"Permanent deposit"
General
The collection is arranged in chronological order.
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--United States.; Industrial relations--United States.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Research Dept.; United States. National Recovery Administration
5511153
- First Hearing on Coat and Suit Code Authority, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  July 20-21
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Code of Fair Practices and Competition, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  September 11
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Code of Fair Practices and Competition, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  October 3
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Code of Fair Practices and Competition, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  November 23
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Code of Fair Practices and Competition, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  November 24
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Code of Fair Practices and Competition, Volume 2, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  January 29
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Conference of Code Authorities and Trade Association Code Committee, Volume 1, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  March 5
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Conference of Code Authorities and Trade Association Code Committee Employment, Volume 2, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  March 6
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Conference of Code Authorities and Trade Association Code Committee, Code Administration and Improvement, Volume 1, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  March 1
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Conference of Code Authorities and Trade Association Code Committee, Trade Practices - Production, Volume 1, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Conference of Code Authorities and Trade Association Code Committee, Code Administration and Improvement, Volume 2, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Conference of Code Authorities and Trade Association Code Committee, Trade Practices - Production, Volume 2, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Conference of Code Authorities and Trade Association Code Committee, Code Administration and Improvement, Volume 3, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  March 7
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Conference of Code Authorities and Trade Association Code Committee, Trade Practices - Production, Volume 3, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Conference of Code Authorities and Trade Association Code Committee, Employment, Volume 3, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Code of Fair Practices and Competition, Volume 1, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  August 3
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing, Cotton Garment, and Dress Manufacturing Industry Amendments, Volume 1, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  June 18
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing, Cotton Garment, and Dress Manufacturing Industries Amendments, Volume 2, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  June 19
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing, Cotton Garment, and Dress Manufacturing Industries Amendments, Volume 2a, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing, Cotton Garment, and Dress Manufacturing Industries Amendments, Volume 3, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  June 20
- U.S. National Industrial Review Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing, Cotton Garment, Dress Manufacturing Industries Amendment, Volume 3a, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing, Cotton Garment, and Dress Manufacturing Industries. Supplement to Hearing, Volume 3b, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing, Cotton Garment, and Dress Manufacturing Industries Amendments, Volume 4, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  June 22
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing, Cotton Garment, and Dress Manufacturing Industries, Amendments, Volume 4a, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Dress Manufacturing Industry Amendments, Volume 1, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  October 9
- U.S. National Industrial Recover Board Hearing on Alleged Violations of the Code for the Dress Manufacturing Industry Against Paris-Maid Dress Company, Volume 1 Part 1, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  November 27
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Alleged Violations of the Code for the Dress Manufacturing Industry Against Paris-Maid Dress Company, Volume 1 Part 2, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Alleged Violations of the Code for the Dress Manufacturing Industry Against Paris-Maid Dress Company, Volume 2, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  November 30
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Alleged Violations of the Code for the Dress Manufacturing Hearing on Alleged Violations of the Code for the Dress Manufacturing Industry Against Paris-Maid Dress Company, Volume 3, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  December 1
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Dress Manufacturing Industry, Amendments to Code of Fair Competition, Volume 4, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  February 26
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Dress Manufacturing Industry, Amendments to Code of Fair Competition - Jobbers Contractors, Volume 5, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  February 27
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Dress Manufacturing Industry, Amendments to Code of Fair Competition - Uniform Order Blanks, Volume 6, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  February 28
- U.S. NRA Division of Review, History of the Code of Fair Competition for the Dress Industry (Appendix), 1935 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- U.S. NRA Division of Review, History of the Code of Fair Competition for the Dress Industry, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing Industry, Proposed Amendments of the Code of Fair Competition, Volume 1, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  February 1
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing Industry, Proposed Amendments to the Code of Fair Competition, Volume 1, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing Industry, Proposed Amendments to the Code of Fair Competition, Volume 2, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  February 2
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing Industry, Proposed Amendments to the Code of Fair Competition, Volume 2, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  February 3
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Men's Clothing Industry, Proposed Amendments of the Code of Fair Competition, Volume 3, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  February 4
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair Competition, Volume 1 Part 1, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  January 30
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair Competition, Volume 1 Part 2, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Complete Index, Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair Competition, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  January 30-February 2
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair Competition, Volume 2 Part 1, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  January 31
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair Competition, Volume 2 Part 2, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair Competition, Volume 3 Part 1, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair Competition, Volume 3 Part 2, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair Competition, Volume 3 Part 3, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Employment Provisions in Codes of Fire Competition, Volume 4, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Dress Manufacturing Industry, Modification Proposal, Volume 2, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  January 7
- U.S. National Industrial Recovery Administration Hearing on Dress Manufacturing Industry, Modification Proposal, Volume 3, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  January 8
- U.S. NRA Division of Review, The Coat and Suit Industry, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- U.S. NRA Division of Review, the Labor Program Under the NRA and Industrial Homework, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- U.S. NRA Division of Review. Trade Practice Provisions in the Codes, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Report of the Special Commission on Wages and Hours in the Fur Manufacturing Industry by Paul Abelson, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Wages and Hours in American Industry, NRA Source Material, by Solomon Barkin., 1936 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Volume 1
- Wages and Hours in American Industry, NRA Source Material, by Solomon Barkin, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Volume 2
- Wages and Hours in American Industry, NRA Source Material, by Solomon Barkin, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Volume 3
- Report of the Commission for the Coat and Suit Industry by George Gordon Battle, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Report of the Special Commission on Wage Differentials in the Cap and Cloth Hat Industry by Paul F. Brissenden, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Report of the Committee on the Economic and Social Implications of the Company Story and Scrip System by Charles B. Fowler, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Financial and Labor Data on the Women's Neckwear and Scarf Industry by W.A. Gill, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- National Labor Income by Months (1929-1935) by Dorothy E. Smith, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Statistical Background of the NRA by Victor S. Szeliski, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Some Aspects of the Women's Apparel Industry by Sherman Trowbridge, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- U.S. Committee of Industrial Analysis, the National Recovery Administration, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Labor's Opportunity Under the Industrial Recovery Act by David Dubinsky (Box 5, Folder 15)